When I was in
college, I
could quite often be
found at 3:00 AM
working on my laptop,
listening to the TV
in the background and
probably
checking my phone
every few minutes.
In those moments when I was
stuck in the
waiting room and
forgot my phone, I
panicked a little.  What would
I do without entertainment?  At
the very least, I
needed to
read something.  To be
clear, there is
nothing wrong with
multitasking
or
enjoying
things that
entertain us and
make time
pass.  However,
years later, I reached a
point where
I felt like the days
were passing by without
much meaning or
purpose, and that I often
felt
overwhelmed,
restless, and
restless if
I had to
spend time doing
nothing.
My thoughts were
running endlessly.  I
wanted to change that.  I
felt like I
needed to do this
to feel more
fulfilled.  I
felt that
learning
to enjoy
tasks that
required
delayed
gratification would be
crucial to
overcoming difficulties
and feeling happier and
more empowered.  So I
decided to
rediscover the lost
art
of monotasking,
doing one thing at a
time.  Something I once
practiced as a
child, when I could
read or play for hours
without
worrying about my
productivity.
When I first started
monotasking, I
noticed two things.
First, I became more
productive
because my usually
distractible "
personality"
improved due to
the ability
to finish
things I started, which
is a constant
practice.  Secondly, the
downside was that
I was incredibly
bored.  I longed to
have something to
entertain my brain
, apart from the current
task.  Sometimes the silence
seemed unbearable
.  But gradually this
feeling passed.  This
took time.  I
have conditioned my mind to be
constantly entertained, and
that is not easy to change.
Gradually, I felt myself
sinking into a calmness I
hadn't felt in a long time
, a sense of
mind-
body connection that
stretched from my
head to my toes
.  I became
hyper-aware of
my thoughts and how I
wanted to practice
deep concentration
to change some of
my internal
dialogues for the better.    For
a long time,
monotasking was
difficult in many
ways, but it
led to something
beautiful.  Now I
can read, write,
and create without the
desperate need
to drown out the silence and
my thoughts.
Now, if I watch a
movie, I just
watch a movie.  If I
listen to music, I
just listen.  Time
spent on
the phone has replaced
many of the things I
enjoy doing more.
Everyday life hasn't
gotten easier, but
it has gotten more interesting,
and I notice a lot
more, and in many
ways I'm
happier.
This may not resonate with you
, but I
thought I'd share
because not too long ago in
human history, we
had no choice but to
monotask.  In
a sense, it is a
secret meditative
art form that
many of us have
forgotten.  Thanks to the
modern world, I
can enjoy a
healthier and
safer life
than my ancestors, and I would
never want to
live in the past, but I
think there are still important
things we can
learn about those
who came before me, and
maybe
monotasking can
be useful for you
.  Let me know how
it turns out.
On another note, the last
few months have been
full of
yard work.  My father
helped me
build embankments, and I
planted all kinds of flowers in the yard
.  Here's a little
peek at what the
garden looks like.  I
grow wild raspberries and
all kinds of herbs.  Lucas is
also working on a
rabbit enclosure.  This will be a
great shelter for
animals throughout the year
so they can
enjoy
nature and
run freely.  I hope to
show
you the completed
project very soon.  I
was working on a
recipe for a
sloe syrup yesterday, and it was
so delicious.
Today I ate the
rest of the ice cream.  I ate
it for breakfast.
I admit, but it
was just too
delicious.  I just couldn't
wait for
dinner.  In the end, I
mixed raspberries,
strawberries, and blueberries, as well as
everything else together.
And it was very interesting.
I think when you
make floral
syrups, it's a pretty
subtle but very
interesting flavor.  I think
lilac is still one of
my favorites.
The drunkenness wasn't as
fragrant as
lilac usually is, but it's still
really fun
to experiment and
just see what
you can come up with.
There are so many
amazing plants to
experiment with.  As
you well know, I've
done quite a few videos on
this channel about me being a
very sensitive
person, a child
prone to, you know,
a little bit more
anxiety about
things, and it was
just natural, and I
realized that because of
certain life
decisions and
lifestyle choices that I had in
the past, my stress and
anxiety had gotten a lot
worse, especially
after, you know
, recovering from being a
workaholic and also
from an eating
disorder.  And this whole
process and a kind of
decade of
rethinking and
reforming my
life has made me have a
surprisingly high
value on not just
mindfulness
in general, becoming a
single-tasker or
a mono-tasker,
just doing one
thing at a time.  I don't do
this every day.  I am a person
who loves
multitasking.  This is
something that comes naturally to me
, and I am a fairly
absent-minded person, as are
several family members.
It, you know, runs
through our, uh,
generations, that's for sure.
However, especially when
I'm feeling stressed or
my mind is racing
, I think this is
such a crucial
time for me to
focus on
one activity at a time
.  When you're really
speeding up and
feeling
overwhelmed or
stressed,
slowing down
and doing one
thing at a time has
had incredible
benefits, at least for me.  And maybe
it will also be
useful for you
the next time
you need
a little relaxation
and stress relief, but
you can't
afford to take a
vacation or break,
and instead sit in the
moment,
be aware of your
breathing, and do
one thing at a time.  That
we have changed our
perception of our
time.  You know, often we
want to be so
efficient right now and
so productive
, doing several
things at once and
speeding up the process of
completing them.  And I
think there's still a
lot of value in
slowing down
and doing one
thing at a time and
finding joy in it
, even
something as
simple as washing
dishes.  You can
search for articles about
doing one
thing at a time and how
this mindful
lifestyle can
have a huge
positive impact on
our brain health
, but it's not easy.
I warn you,
it can seem
unbearably boring at times.  Your
brain is so
stimulated that it
can feel almost
frustrating and very
difficult to slow down
at that level.  So
be prepared for
this, and it will pass with time
.  I don't know if
any of this will be
useful to you.  I have no
idea, but it kind of
affected me, and it
seems like there's a
lot of research
that raises
a lot of interesting
questions as well, maybe we
should approach
our time differently.
Perhaps
efficiency and
productivity
can sometimes turn
from a very healthy and
wonderful state,
perhaps sometimes
losing track of the day and
forgetting to appreciate the
truly important and
meaningful moments.  With
all that said, I'll
leave you with this.
Thank you very much for
being with me today
.  It was certainly a
quiet evening,
hopefully a pleasant one,
and I hope it
at least brought you a
moment of peace.  So
I'm sending you lots of
love.  Thank you for your
support of my
work as an artist.
I am very grateful that
I can keep this
space free of
advertising in the middle of my
videos and not engage in
sponsorship.  And this is
so important to me
in terms of creating a
peaceful harbor on
this channel.  So,
thank you very much.  Sending
so much love.
Goodbye.